visions.ca 2018-09-05

# Privacy Policy | Visions Electronics

****Introduction:**** ** ******

At Visions Electronics our relationship with you, our customer, is of paramount importance to us. We will always do everything necessary to ensure that we protect all of your personal information, and keep it safe and secure. We do not, and will not, sell or rent your personal information to anyone.

We have taken steps to ensure that we meet or exceed all of the principles established by federal and provincial governments with regard to the collection of, and handling of, any of your personal information we collect during our business dealings together.

**Visions Electronics – 10 Principles for Privacy Protection:**

**1.) Accountability** – Visions Electronics is 100% accountable for all aspects of ensuring that we follow both our own internal guidelines for privacy protection, as well as all government legislated rules. To this end, we have established a set of guidelines which we follow with regard to the collection and handling of any data, and we have a Privacy Officer who is responsible to ensure that these guidelines are followed.

**2.) Identifying Purposes** – At the time we ask you to provide any personal information, we will inform you of the reason why the information is required. For the purposes for which information is collected on this website, please refer to the section below entitled “Website Information Collection Methods and Purposes”

**3.) Consent** – We will not collect any information about you without your consent. You are not obligated to provide any information to us, although we may require certain information in order to be able to fulfill a service to you. For example, in order to be able to provide a delivery service to your house, we would need your name, address and phone number. By having provided this information, your consent is implied. Other situations will require your express consent, for example if you apply for a credit card with us, we will expressly ask you for your permission for us to share your credit information with the 3rd party credit card provider.

**4.) Limiting Collection** – We will only collect your personal information where it is necessary for the specified purpose, such as the examples in item (3) above.

**5.) Limiting Use, Disclosure, and Retention** – We will use and disclose your personal information only for the use for which it was collected, unless you have authorized us otherwise, or as required by Law. We will only retain your information for as long as necessary to satisfy the purposes for which it was collected.

**6.) Accuracy** – We are committed to keeping your personal information as accurate, complete and up to date as necessary, taking into account the purposes for which we collected the information.

**7.) Safeguards** – Visions Electronics is committed to maintaining the security of your information to protect you against unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. 

**8.) Openness** – Visions Electronics is committed to addressing any questions you may have regarding any aspect of our handling of your personal information which we have collected.

**9.) Customer Ability to Access Information** – In the event that you would like to contact us to obtain information about your private information at Visions Electronics, please send us a written request. This request can be mailed attn: Privacy Officer 6009 – 1A Street SW, Calgary AB T2H 0G5 or emailed to [privacy.officer@visions.ca](mailto:privacy.officer@visions.ca)

**10.) Your Recourse** – We are committed to handling any question or concern about our privacy principles or practices promptly. You can contact our Chief Privacy Officer at the address in item (9) above. In the event that we have not been able to resolve any issue, you can contact the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada. The website address for the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada is [www.privcom.gc.c](http://www.privcom.gc.ca/)

**Website Information Collection Methods and Purposes:**

**1.) Personal Information:**

For the purposes of our website, we collect name, address, phone number, e-mail and credit card information at the time you place an order. This information is stored in the form of a personal profile. The purpose(s) for collecting this personal information is to allow us to complete your order and arrange delivery, have a tracking process for warranty fulfillment down the road if your product requires repair, administer rebates and other special programs, and to contact you in the event any communication is needed with regard to your order. We also collect similar information (minus the credit card info) on our website for the purposes of e-mail newsletter sign-up. If you have signed up for our e-mail newsletter, you will always have the opportunity to “opt out” and ask us to discontinue sending the automated e-mail. Some personal information is shared with 3rd parties where necessary, such as your credit card info is shared with the credit card processing company to protect against fraudulent use of your credit card. Your personal information profile can be viewed by you at any time, and you have the ability to update and change it within the site.

**2.) Non-Personal Information:**

Like most other websites, our website also compiles non-personal information regarding website users. This information does not identify you. Examples include the Internet Protocol address (IP address) of your computer, the IP address of your Internet service provider, the type of operating system you are using, the website sections and pages you visit including what images have been viewed, the time and date that you visited the website, the IP address of the website from which you linked to our website, and the content you download from our website. The above information is used by us for system and website administration, and to provide general statistics regarding the use of our website such as determining what products and sections are the most popular or which of our marketing campaigns are having the most impact. None of this non-personal information can be connected to any particular user to reveal their identity. Non-personal information may be shared with 3rd parties for reporting purposes. 

**3.) Cookies:**

Our website also makes use of Cookies. Cookies are small bits of computer information that reside on your computers hard drive. This information will identify your computer when you visit our site, so we can enhance your convenience and use of our site. You have the option of disabling the use of cookies by adjusting the settings in your internet browser, but doing so may limit your ability to access and use certain features of our website.

**4.) Links to Other Websites:**

Our website may contain links to other websites. If you click on one of these links, you are leaving Visions Electronics website, and will be accessing a website belonging to a 3rd party. Visions Electronics has no responsibility for, or control over, those websites. We encourage you to read and understand the privacy policies of those other sites prior to use, to ensure you are comfortable with how they collect and use information about you.

Updated Aug 9, 2017.
